smashboards.com 2019-09-27

# Privacy policy | Smashboards

_We are Smashboards (referred to in this document as “we”, “our”, or “us”), and are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This policy covers information about your information that is stored on this website. If you have any additional questions about your personal information, you may contact us via the[Staff Announcements and User Feedback Forum](https://smashboards.com/forums/677/)._

When a person registers for Smashboards, they must provide select details about oneself to create an account. These details construct a user's profile and allow one to diversify themselves on the site. Some of this data, however, is fairly crucial to oneself, and must be safeguarded. We retain this data and allows a user to make modifications to most details at any time, and in the case of crucial details, make sure that information is safeguarded.

This policy covers details about both the Personally Identifiable Information (referred to in this document thereon as PII) and non-Personally Identifiable Information (referred to in this document thereon as non-PII), as well as what actions you as a person can take to manage, modify and remove your information on our site.

### What information do we hold about you?

> The primary PII that we collect and process may vary. At the minimum, the following is collected for an account:
> 
>   * Your name that you use for this site (your username).
>   * Your age.
>   * Your email address.
>   * Your IP addresses used when you log onto this website and post content, and is PII in conjunction with the other pieces of data collected.
> 

> 
> Additional, non-PII data that is collected includes:
> 
>   * Fields that you fill out on your profile (such as a location, which may constitute as PII depending on what you fill out for it).
>   * Additional outlets of contact, provided that you fill out the Contact form on your profile.
> 

> 
> Your data is collected in these cases:
> 
>   * You register and confirm your account on this website.
>   * You fill out your contact form with outside accounts for different applications and websites.
>   * You browse this site and view the forums.
>   * You post content, through regular posts, profile posts or through Conversations.
>   * You fill out additional fields on your profile.
> 

### How is your personal information used?

> Your data is used in the following ways:
> 
>   * When you confirm your account and login, your data is used to log yourself in and keep you as a registered member of the site.
>   * Your age is used to ensure that the site complies with various legal standards for user accounts throughout the internet, such as [COPPA](https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/rules/rulemaking-regulatory-reform-proceedings/childrens-online-privacy-protection-rule) (Children's Online Privacy Protection Act).
>   * Your email address is used to inform you of activity on our site, such as messages or conversations directed as you.
>   * Your IP address is tracked whenever you take actions on our site, including posting messages. Your IP address is never visible to regular users.
> 

> 
> Other ways we use your information:
> 
>   * Additional, non-PII (such as your browser or device type) may be tracked to adjust the appearance of the site for analytical purposes, such as tracking the number of visitors who look at our website.
>   * Your email may be messaged with major announcements, notifications or site-wide newsletters, which can be opted out of through a user's [Preferences](https://smashboards.com/account/preferences) page.
>   * Should you wish to reset your account’s password, your email will be messaged with instructions on how to do so.
> 

### Keeping your data secure

> We are committed to making sure any data that you provide us is secured. While some information and the visibility of your details is often open to a user’s leisure, your IP and email address are never publicly displayed. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in suitable measures to safeguard and secure information that we collected; in the event of a data breach, we will inform the public within 72 hours.

### Cookie Policy

> Cookies are small text files, set by us put on your device, that allow us to provide certain functionalities to you. These include:
> 
>   * Remembering your login information and having it locally stored so you do not have to login on each browsing session.
>   * Keeping your preferences across a device for repeated visits.
> 

> 
> We have a detailed cookie policy, which can be read [here](https://smashboards.com/help/cookies/).

### Advertisements

> Regular users will see advertisements that are on the website; Users with Premium accounts will not see these. These advertisements are curated based upon one's general details and non-PII, while also selected to follow privacy policy and content policy our ad provider entails. Advertisements are expected to not include the following:
> 
>   * Cookies that obtain and track personally identifiable data.
>   * Content that violates our guidelines, such as including uninitiated audio, pop ups, or automatic re-directions.
>   * Content that violates our Terms of Service.
> 

> 
> If you come across an advertisement that appears to be in violation of these guidelines, please use our [Bad Advertisement](https://smashboards.com/applications/42/apply/) application and answer the questions that follow.

### Rights

> As a user, you are able to access your information and change the majority of it at your own leisure through the User Control Panel; you also have a right to access the data we hold about you and may request an Administration copy of it in the [Help From A Smashboards Admin Forum](https://smashboards.com/forums/679/), and if you feel that it is inaccurate, you may ask us in that forum to correct or complete that information.
> 
> You also have the right to change visibility of your account and keep certain details, such as your age or profile, inaccessible from general users. These can be set from a user's [Privacy](https://smashboards.com/account/privacy) page.
> 
> Any warnings that you as a user attain are not visible to regular users, but will be visible to staff for historical & moderation purposes. We will not authorize the retrieval of your records for other users.
> 
> Furthermore, you have the right to erasure; you may request the deletion of your account through our [Account Deletion Request](https://smashboards.com/applications/40/apply) form. This process will delete the majority of profile information and data; please note that users suspected of abusing the account deletion feature may have non-personal identifiable information stored on the site when an account is deleted.

### Acceptance of this policy

> You accept this policy by browsing our website and having an account registered with us; if you do not wish to abide by this policy, then we ask that you do not use this website. When you register an account, you are explicitly asked for your acceptance of this Privacy Policy.
> 
> In addition, we may make changes to this policy at any time; if major changes are made, you may be asked to review and re-accept this policy.
